<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-08-14T00:17:51+09:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Patrick’s Personal Blogs</title><subtitle>Patrick is a highly versatile agricultural professional in Australia</subtitle><author><name>Patrick Di</name></author><entry><title type="html">First Day as a PhD Student</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025-08-03-First-Day-as-a-PhD-Student/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Day as a PhD Student" /><published>2025-08-03T00:15:00+09:30</published><updated>2025-08-03T00:15:00+09:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/First%20Day%20as%20a%20PhD%20Student</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025-08-03-First-Day-as-a-PhD-Student/"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p><em>This post celebrates the official start of my Doctor of Philosophy (PhD) journey at CQUniversity Australia.</em> <br /></p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Patrick Di</name></author><category term="life" /><category term="event" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post celebrates the official start of my Doctor of Philosophy (PhD) journey at CQUniversity Australia.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">NT Agri Study Maps Online Now</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025-05-25-NTAgriMaps-Online/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NT Agri Study Maps Online Now" /><published>2025-05-25T22:20:00+09:30</published><updated>2025-05-25T22:20:00+09:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/NTAgriMaps%20Online</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025-05-25-NTAgriMaps-Online/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="nt-agri-study-maps-online-now">NT Agri Study Maps Online Now!</h1>

<p><strong><em>An interactive map for The Northern Territory Agriculture Land Suitability Series (Study Areas 2014-2022)</em></strong></p>

<p><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/patrickaxe/NTAgriStudyMaps/main/docs/Screenshot.png" alt="Screenshot" /></p>

<p>You can access this new webpage through <a href="https://patrickaxe.github.io/NTAgriStudyMaps/">GitHub landing page</a> or <a href="https://paddyrice.shinyapps.io/NTAgriStudyMaps/">ShinyApp page</a></p>

<p>[Ends]</p>]]></content><author><name>Patrick Di</name></author><category term="shinyapp" /><category term="agriculture" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[NT Agri Study Maps Online Now!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A journey to Adelaide as an ACYD delegate</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024-12-01-ACYD-in-Adelaide/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A journey to Adelaide as an ACYD delegate" /><published>2024-12-01T19:05:00+09:30</published><updated>2024-12-01T19:05:00+09:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ACYD%20in%20Adelaide</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024-12-01-ACYD-in-Adelaide/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="a-reflection-from-the-14th-acyd">A reflection from the 14<sup>th</sup> ACYD</h1>

<p><strong><em>A unique lens of Australia-China Bilateral relations</em></strong></p>

<p><em>Disclaimer: Opinions expressed are solely my own and do not express the views or opinions of my employer.</em></p>

<h1 id="background">Background</h1>

<p>Attending the 14<sup>th</sup> <a href="https://www.acyd.org.au/" target="_blank">Australia-China Youth Dialogue</a> is truly a privilege. With thirty brightest minds hailing from Australia and China across various fields, we gathered together in Adelaide from 22<sup>nd</sup> November to 25<sup>th</sup> November, 2024. <br /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/media/2024-12-01/IMG_5486.jpg" alt="A beautiful bird's-eye view from the red centre, while I was stop over Alice Spring Airport en route to Adelaide" title="Macdonnell Ranges" /></p>

<p>At the time of the blossoming season of jacaranda in Adelaide, we were fortunate to hear the views from prestigious speakers over the sixteen sessions within the theme of <strong>“Planning for the Future by Learning from the Past”</strong> (Chinese:<em>从过去，见未来</em>). This Dialogue covered a range of topics from re-engagement between two nations, heated geo-political tensions to arts and sustainability. <br /></p>

<h1 id="site-visit---wolf-blass-winery">Site Visit - Wolf Blass Winery</h1>

<p>As an agricultural professional, visiting the <a href="https://www.wolfblass.com/">Wolf Blass Winery</a> was one of the most memorable highlights. <br /></p>

<p>According to the South Australian Government <a href="https://statedevelopment.sa.gov.au/news/sas-wine-exports-flow-past-1-5-billion">website</a>, South Australia contributed 67 per cent to the total value of Australian wines exports, which reached $2.32 billion (up 14.65 per cent). <br /></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>China remains an important two-way trading partner for South Australia with merchandise exports the highest on record at $4.23 billion to the end of June 2024.<sup>[1]</sup><br /></p>
</blockquote>

<p>For many Australian agricultural producers, particularly the wine industry, China is a major player in the global commodity market. Even though the trade disputes and many efforts into market diversification over the last couple of years, Chinese market still dominates the shares of Australia’s exports destinations - as Australia’s exports to China rose 18% to a record $219 billion in 2023, or 32% of total exports according to Export Finance Australia<sup>[2]</sup>.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/media/2024-12-01/IMG_5503.jpg" alt="Learning about how to make wine!" title="Wolf Blass Winery" /></p>

<h1 id="take-home-message">Take-home Message</h1>

<p>In our last day, our journey reached its climax when Her Excellency the Honourable Frances Adamson AC, <a href="https://www.governor.sa.gov.au/governor-of-south-australia/about-the-governor">the 36<sup>th</sup> Governor of South Australia</a>, hosted a reception at South Australian Government House. She was also the 12<sup>th</sup> Australian Ambassador to China from 2011 to 2015. <br /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/media/2024-12-01/IMG_5531.jpg" alt="Government House View" title="SA Government House" /></p>

<p>Throughout the Dialogue, we learnt many perspectives on Australia-China Bilateral relations. For both nations, there is no doubt that only the co-operation brings prosperity and mutual benefits. Amidst the rise of populism and protectionism, we need to cherish the peaceful moments we have. After all, there is still room for potential collaborations.</p>

<p>In the end, although there are many differences between two nations, <strong>keeping engaging</strong> plays a pivotal and centric role in building a stable bilateral relationship between Australia and China.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><em>A relationship where we can cooperate where we can, disagree where we must, and engage in the national interest.</em> <sup>[3]</sup></p>
</blockquote>

<h1 id="acknowledgement">Acknowledgement</h1>
<p>The author would like to acknowledge the management team from Australia-China Youth Dialogue for organising and curating this fantastic event so seamlessly. The author also would like to thank to all supporters and sponsors for making this event possible, particularly the <a href="https://www.australiachinafoundation.org.au/">National Foundation for Australia-China Relations</a> (NFACR) (Chinese: <em>澳中基金会</em>).</p>

<h1 id="references">References</h1>
<p>[1] South Australian Government Department of State Development (2024, August 22) <em>SA’s wine exports flow past $1.5 billion</em>, South Australian Government Department of State Development, https://statedevelopment.sa.gov.au/news/sas-wine-exports-flow-past-1-5-billion. <br />
[2] Export Finance Australia (2024, July) <em>China—Record imports from Australia, but economic headwinds mount</em>, Export Finance Australia, https://www.exportfinance.gov.au/resources/world-risk-developments/2024/july/china-record-imports-from-australia-but-economic-headwinds-mount/. <br />
[3] Wong, P. (2024, August 16) <em>Opening remarks at the eighth Australia-China High Level Dialogue</em>, Minister for Foreign Affairs, https://www.foreignminister.gov.au/minister/penny-wong/speech/opening-remarks-eighth-australia-china-high-level-dialogue.</p>

<p>[Ends]</p>]]></content><author><name>Patrick Di</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="journey" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A reflection from the 14th ACYD]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">One Week over Mint OS (Linux-Ubuntu) Drama</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024-11-17-One-Week-over-Mint-OS-(Linux-Ubuntu)-Drama/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One Week over Mint OS (Linux-Ubuntu) Drama" /><published>2024-11-17T02:00:14+09:30</published><updated>2024-11-17T02:00:14+09:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/One%20Week%20over%20Mint%20OS%20(Linux-Ubuntu)%20Drama</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024-11-17-One-Week-over-Mint-OS-(Linux-Ubuntu)-Drama/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="background">Background</h1>
<p>Several weeks ago, I bought a new PC with a dual operating system - Windows 11 and Mint OS installed. Last weekend, I finally got some free time to modify brand-new Mint OS. But this is what the whole drama really started.</p>

<p>Linux (and Ubuntu) weren’t new to me. I used them when I was a research student in the university - installing Ubuntu and Tails OS systems on a Raspberry Pi module or a USB stick, using some Linux command lines on Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL) for fun. Before that, I have also been using Mac OS system (a UNIX-based system) for approximately six years (also using Wine containers or Parallels Desktop Virtual Machine for accessing Windows based software for my studies, such as APSIM). However, this time was my <em>FIRST</em> time really seriously using Linux.</p>

<p>To be fair and honest, I am not good at coding. Coding for me has been a steep learning curve for last four years.  Before downloading and installing Linux permanently, I have already heard from people that coding is essential to use Linux, and this is probably because Linux is easily broken - many of basic uses involve coding and troubleshooting, such as installing the software by <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">sudo apt-get install</code>.</p>

<p><strong>Challenges accepted!</strong></p>

<h1 id="issue-1---step-into-a-trap">Issue 1 - Step into a “trap”</h1>
<p>While I was using the Mint OS, my cursor couldn’t move around. Luckily, the keyboard was working, and I did not feel panic about it, because I mentally prepared for anything going wrong. However, this time I didn’t realise I went too far!</p>

<p>I forced the PC to shut down, and attempted to restart in the hope of resolving the issue automatically picked up by the system. Unfortunately, it didn’t, so I was looking for the possible solution online.</p>

<p><em>Many seconds, hours, days have gone through</em> <strong>Oops, I messed up the boot</strong></p>

<p><img src="/assets/media/2024-11-17/2024-11-11-234606_002.jpeg" alt="I did many starts" title="BIOS display" /></p>

<h1 id="issue-2---cant-boot-up-the-mint-os">Issue 2 - Can’t boot up the Mint OS</h1>
<p>It was bit late that I couldn’t boot up Mint OS. At the beginning, I was bit annoyed but I was optimistic that I could fix it up. Over the course of several nights, while I was searching the possible solutions, I started losing patience, and felt upset that I wouldn’t be able to use Linux at all in near future. Then I was thinking it might be a good idea to reinstall another Linux-based OS, such as Arch OS or Debian OS. I gave it up after I was attempting to install them. It was a very <em>complicated</em> process. <br />
<img src="/assets/media/2024-11-17/2024-11-12-132835_002.jpeg" alt="Installation for Debian OS" title="Debian error" />
<img src="/assets/media/2024-11-17/2024-11-12-212255_002.jpeg" alt="Installation for Arch OS" title="No idea..." /></p>

<h1 id="pivotal-success">Pivotal success</h1>
<p>While I was talking my friend, I learnt that there is a boot repair tool from <a href="https://help.ubuntu.com/community/Boot-Repair" target="_blank">Ubuntu</a> might be able to help me from this situation. I wipe the only USB out and to boot the live session from this boot repair tool. I followed the instruction, and it did not help. I have to seek the help from other people on <a href="https://ubuntuforums.org/showthread.php?t=2502458" target="_blank">Ubuntu Forum</a>.</p>

<p>On the second day, I discovered the boot was deleted from the booting list. The solution code as follows: <br />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">root@ubuntu:~# efibootmgr -c -w -L "Mint" -d /dev/nvme0n1p5 -p 1 -l /efi/ubuntu/grubx64.efi </code></p>

<h1 id="distorted-display-resolution">Distorted display resolution</h1>
<p>Cheerful moment didn’t last for a long time. 
<img src="/assets/media/2024-11-17/2024-11-16-182422_002.jpeg" alt="Scale can't be modified" title="too large!!" /></p>

<p>I found you can actually set up a new mode for this display by following these codes:</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">cvt 1920 1200</code> # it will give the output for <em>Modeline “1920x1080_60.00”  173.00  1920 2048 2248 2576  1080 1083 1088 1120 -hsync +vsync</em> 
<br />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">xrandr --newmode  "1920x1080_60.00"  173.00  1920 2048 2248 2576  1080 1083 1088 1120 -hsync +vsync</code>
<br />
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">xrandr --addmode None-1 "1920x1080_60.00"</code></p>

<p>But this gave me a <strong>black</strong> screen! At least, I can still boot up, so I tried the last resort - Recovery mode.</p>

<p><em>Eventually, successfully done!</em></p>]]></content><author><name>Patrick Di</name></author><category term="linux" /><category term="experience" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Background Several weeks ago, I bought a new PC with a dual operating system - Windows 11 and Mint OS installed. Last weekend, I finally got some free time to modify brand-new Mint OS. But this is what the whole drama really started.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">This is my first post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024-11-09-This-is-my-first-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="This is my first post" /><published>2024-11-09T22:23:14+09:30</published><updated>2024-11-09T22:23:14+09:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/This%20is%20my%20first%20post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024-11-09-This-is-my-first-post/"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p><em>This is my first post.</em> <br />
<em>仅作留念。</em></p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>Patrick Di</name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is my first post. 仅作留念。]]></summary></entry></feed>